<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About-us on Brady &amp; Associates: Hospital Organizational Specialists</title>
    <link>http://www.bradyinc.com/about-us/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in About-us on Brady &amp; Associates: Hospital Organizational Specialists</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Brady &amp; Associates</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:27:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.bradyinc.com/about-us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>http://www.bradyinc.com/about-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:27:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bradyinc.com/about-us/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It is possible to spend unbelievable amounts of money on reporting services that will produce terabytes of data, the overwhelming majority of which will never be used by anyone. Since 1983 Brady &amp;amp; Associates has served more than 750 health care clients in the U.S., Europe, Canada and Middle East. In the course of that work, we developed &lt;em&gt;The First Law of Practical Analytics&lt;/em&gt; which can be stated as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data are &lt;u&gt;not&lt;/u&gt; information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information is &lt;u&gt;not&lt;/u&gt; understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding is &lt;u&gt;not&lt;/u&gt; a solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is that hospitals can buy reams of “data” from any number of companies. The difference is that we bring &lt;u&gt;information&lt;/u&gt;, &lt;u&gt;understanding&lt;/u&gt; and &lt;u&gt;solutions&lt;/u&gt; to the table. For more than 30 years, we have used data, systems thinking, and change management techniques to help hospitals improve their organizational effectiveness. Unlike benchmarking services designed by database programmers, our services are created around knowledge gained from decades of research into the factors that limit human productivity in the clinical setting, Our services enable you to actually &lt;u&gt;do something&lt;/u&gt; concrete with our results. Practical usability makes all the difference in the world. That’s one of the reasons we are consultants to consultants and have partnered with such internationally recognized firms as McKinsey &amp;amp; Company, The Lewin Group, Aon Hewitt, and BKD. We serve as a resource to AHA and HFMA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-the-beginning&#34;&gt;From the Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;img-left&#34; src=&#34;http://www.bradyinc.com/img/frank_brady-brady_associates_president_hospital_benchmark.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Atlanta hospital organizational specialists, Kansas City hospital organizational specialists&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Brady, President of Brady &amp;amp; Associates, began a life-long pursuit in 1971 when he managed a field-test of techniques to measure and improve organizational effectiveness in the clinical setting under the auspices of the Department of Health, Education and Welfare (now the Department of Health and Human Services). That experience provided the unique insight into performance-limiting factors around which our services are designed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank served as CEO in community, Catholic and proprietary hospitals before founding Brady &amp;amp; Associates in 1983. His articles have appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Organizational Effectiveness&lt;/em&gt; newsletter and in &lt;em&gt;Health Progress&lt;/em&gt;, the Official Journal of the Catholic Health Association of the United States. He is a frequent speaker at HFMA-sponsored events and has served as a consultant to consultants for such internationally recognized firms such as The Lewin Group, Aeon Hewitt, and McKinsey &amp;amp; Company. For more than thirty years Brady &amp;amp; Associates has supported the management initiatives of more than 750 hospitals of all sizes, missions and ownership types throughout the U.S. as well as in Europe, Canada and the Middle East. The firm employs data, systems thinking, and change management principles to maximize organizational effectiveness. Frank holds a Masters degree in Health Services Administration from the University of Missouri at Kansas City. The father of five children, he and his wife Donna live in Kansas City.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>