<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Impact-staffing-reviews-rsses on Brady &amp; Associates</title>
    <link>http://www.bradyinc.com/impact-staffing-reviews/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Impact-staffing-reviews-rsses on Brady &amp; Associates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Brady &amp; Associates</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 20:41:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.bradyinc.com/impact-staffing-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Staffing Reviews</title>
      <link>http://www.bradyinc.com/impact-staffing-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 20:41:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bradyinc.com/impact-staffing-reviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IMPACT Staffing Reviews&lt;/em&gt;: The heart of this powerful labor management resource is our proprietary database which contains validated staffing and activity information from more than 750 hospitals, 304 distinct department types, and 24,000 hospital departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The review&amp;rsquo;s workload-based staffing benchmarks allow the hospital to develop, calibrate, and adjust department-level staffing standards. This is critically important given today&amp;rsquo;s frequent, dramatic, unanticipated, and unpredictable utilization changes. Department reports measure workload-based productivity, hours worked to hours paid ratios, and overtime use. Each department is compared against the actual range of performance observed within peer groups individually selected to match your departments&amp;rsquo; intrinsic characteristics and workload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started is quick and easy. The set up phase is unobtrusive and non-disruptive. Specialized algorithms &amp;ldquo;scrub&amp;rdquo; your data, testing relationships within and across departments to identify and resolve potential errors. Initial reports are typically available within 30 days after kick off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apples-to-apples concerns and &amp;ldquo;uniqueness arguments&amp;rdquo;, the classic impediments to successful benchmarking efforts in the past, are addressed and neutralized head on. &amp;ldquo;Buy in&amp;rdquo; is further fostered by our focus on educating department managers about IMPACT&amp;rsquo;s unique peer group selection process and by individually obtaining their input at the start of the process before any numbers are &amp;ldquo;crunched&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, our services provide the potential to receive much more than just numbers. Because our services are designed around an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bradyinc.com/about-us/&#34; title=&#34;About Us&#34;&gt;understanding of the factors that limit human productivity&lt;/a&gt; in the clinical setting, staffing review results open the door to the possibility of identifying, prioritizing and resolving them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about how you can obtain an IMPACT Staffing Review for your hospital, select &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:scheduling@bradyinc.com?Subject=Conference Schedule&amp;Body=Please%20schedule%20a%20telephone%20or%20videoconference%20to%20discuss%20IMPACT%E2%80%99s%20services%20in%20the%20context%20of%20our%20priorities.&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. We will schedule a video conference with your senior management team to help you determine if our services are a good fit for current priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>